Being autistic means I need clarity. I need understanding of information. I need to
understand everything about it. When I question what you've asked me or what you've told me
or the information you've provided me, I'm not questioning you. I'm not questioning your
authority. I'm not questioning why it is you're telling me something. I'm trying to understand
it in its entirety. For me, if I don't have the full picture, it's hard for me to engage in a task
because what if there's a variable I've missed? There's lots of elements of this that make
information difficult for me unless I have the full picture. I love information. I love being
able to work with it. Without having what seems as clarity to myself, I will find it hard to follow
the information or to utilise it. People need to start seeing autistic need for clarity as part of
the experience that we struggle with. We need it to be able to move on smoother with our day,
with our tasks, with our job, with whatever it might be. Simple as that.
This has been the cause of so much strife in so many personal and professional spaces where people
feel like me asking questions is me trying to undermine them, me trying to interrogate them,
me trying to prove them wrong. And it's like, no, I'm really, I'm trying to understand because I want
to get to the solution or I want to be able to be the most useful self possible.
So thank you for really putting this so eloquently because it is speaking to my soul.